<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <p>
    This section contains documentation for implementers from both the clinical and technical
    perspectives. The process documentation describes the assumptions and decisions made, as well
    as a functional description of the recommendations.
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li><a href="process-documentation.html">Process Documentation</a></li>
    <li><a href="recommendation-01.html">Recommendation #1 - Nonpharmacologic and Nonopioid Pharmacologic Therapy Consideration</a></li>
    <li><a href="recommendation-02.html">Recommendation #2 - Prioritize Nonopioid Pain Therapies</a></li>
    <li><a href="recommendation-03.html">Recommendation #3 - Opioid Immediate Release Form When Starting Opioid Therapy</a></li>
    <li><a href="recommendation-04-05.html">Recommendations #4 and #5 - Lowest Effective Dose</a></li>
    <li><a href="recommendation-06.html">Recommendation #6 - Prescribe Lowest Effective Dose and Duration</a></li>
    <li><a href="recommendation-07.html">Recommendation #7 - Opioid Therapy Risk Assessment</a></li>
    <li><a href="recommendation-08.html">Recommendation #8 - Naloxone Consideration</a></li>
    <li><a href="recommendation-09.html">Recommendation #9 - Consider Patient's History of Controlled Substance Prescriptions</a></li>
    <li><a href="recommendation-10.html">Recommendation #10 - Urine Drug Testing</a></li>
    <li><a href="recommendation-11.html">Recommendation #11 - Concurrent Use of Opioids and Benzodiazepines</a></li>
    <li><a href="recommendation-12.html">Recommendation #12 - Evidence-based Treatment for Patients with Opioid Use Disorder</a></li>
  </ul>
  <p></p>
  <a name="pilot-testing-reports"> </a>
  <h3 class="title">Pilot Testing Reports</h3>
  <table class="grid">
    <thead>
      <tr>
        <th>Recommendation</th>
        <th>Pilot Site</th>
        <th>Test Period</th>
        <th>Version Tested</th>
        <th>Functionality Validated</th>
        <th>Functionality Not Validated</th>
        <th>Comments</th>
      </tr>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
      <tr >
        <td>4</td>
        <td>Yale</td>
        <td>2020</td>
        <td>patient-view</td>
        <td>Alert when there is extended release prescribed instead of immediate release</td>
        <td></td>
        <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>10</td>
        <td>Yale</td>
        <td>2020</td>
        <td>patient-view</td>
        <td>Alert when there has been no UDS for patient in past year</td>
        <td></td>
        <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>11</td>
        <td>Yale</td>
        <td>2020</td>
        <td>patient-view</td>
        <td>Alert when co-prescribing with benzos</td>
        <td></td>
        <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>12</td>
        <td>Yale</td>
        <td>2020</td>
        <td>patient-view</td>
        <td>Alert is triggered when patient has been diagnosis for OUD</td>
        <td></td>
        <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>10</td>
        <td>Duke</td>
        <td>2020</td>
        <td>patient-view</td>
        <td>Alert when there has been no UDS for patient in past year</td>
        <td></td>
        <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>11</td>
        <td>Duke</td>
        <td>2020</td>
        <td>patient-view</td>
        <td>Alert when co-prescribing with benzos</td>
        <td></td>
        <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>10</td>
        <td>Yale</td>
        <td>2021</td>
        <td>order-sign </td>
        <td>Will alert when there has been no UDS for patient in past year</td>
        <td></td>
        <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>10</td>
        <td>Yale</td>
        <td>2021</td>
        <td>order-sign with suggestion card </td>
        <td>Creates an order for a UDS when a patient has not had a UDS in the past year</td>
        <td></td>
        <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>10</td>
        <td>Duke</td>
        <td>2021</td>
        <td>order-sign</td>
        <td>If a patient has not had a UDS, then the alert recommends a UDS. If the patient did have a UDS in the past year and tested positive for cocaine or PCP an alert was issued.</td>
        <td></td>
        <td>When Duke configured the BPA to create a UDS order (as opposed to using a suggestion card), it resulted in a loop when the user accepted the alert. Accepting the alert resulted in an order-sign event that triggered the CDS service. The only way to break the alert was to decline the recommendation. This was not an issue at Yale. </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>8</td>
        <td>Colorado</td>
        <td>2022</td>
        <td>order-sign</td>
        <td>The MME calculation was disabled in the version of Rec 8 that was integration tested. The test case that was validated was co-prescribing with a benzo. This produce an alert recommending naloxone.</td>
        <td>Integration testing was conducted for one use case - co-prescribing with a benzo. Other recommendation conditions such as history of SUD and daily MME &gt;=50 we not validated. An MME calculation was not conducted as part of this testing. </td>
        <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>10</td>
        <td>Colorado</td>
        <td>2022</td>
        <td>order-sign</td>
        <td>Validated base use case of a patient who has not had a UDS in the past year. Focus was on documenting performance with response times of under a second. </td>
        <td>Enhanced functionality around unexpected test results was not tested.</td>
        <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>10</td>
        <td>MUSC</td>
        <td>2022</td>
        <td>order-sign</td>
        <td>Validated base use case of a patient who has not had a UDS in the past year. Also validated alerts for positive results for cocaine, PCP, and opiates. </td>
        <td></td>
        <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>11</td>
        <td>MUSC</td>
        <td>2022</td>
        <td>order-select</td>
        <td>Validate co-prescribing alert both for patients with pending benzo order and an existing opioid order and for patients with a pending opioid order and existing benzo order. </td>
        <td></td>
        <td></td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>
</div>
